柯克：舰长日志，星历5784.2
KIRK: Captain's log, stardate 5784.2.
响应来自未知星球的求救信号
Responding to distress calls from an unknown planet.
史波克先生无法解释这一点，因为他报告说这个星球上没有生命
Mr. Spock is unable to account for this as he reported no life on the planet.
它拥有丰富的基洛奈德矿藏，是一种稀有且耐用的强大能量资源
It is rich in kironide deposits, a rare and long-lasting source of great power.
男人：你来自星舰企业号吗？
MAN: Are you from the spaceship Enterprise?
是的
That's right.
亚历山大，竭诚为您服务
Alexander, at your service.
我会唱歌，跳舞，玩各种游戏
I sing, dance, play a variety of games.
我是一个非常经得起输的人，请记住这一点
And I'm a very good loser. Please try to bear that in mind.
但现在，请你陪我好吗？
But now, would you please accompany me?
谁是这个星球的居民？
Who are the inhabitants of this planet?
柏拉图人
Platonians.
我们的母星恒星是桑达纳
Our native star is Sahndara.
在它变成新星之前，我们逃脱了
Just before it went nova, we escaped.
我们的领袖喜欢柏拉图的思想
Our leader liked Plato's ideas.
我们的哲人王帕门称我们为柏拉图的孩子
Our philosopher-king, Parmen, calls us Plato's Children,
尽管我们认为我们更像是柏拉图的继子
although we think of ourselves more as Plato's stepchildren.
对不起，有人在等你
Excuse me, someone's waiting for you.
- 欢迎，谁是医生？  - 我是，有什么问题？
- Welcome. Who is the physician? - I am. What's the problem?
我的配偶，他的腿，到这来
My spouse, his leg. Come this way.
那条腿怎么了？
What happened to that leg?
- 我想我划破了它  - 应该立即处理
- I suppose I scratched it. - It should've been attended to at once.
纯粹的无知，你有什么可以做的吗？
Sheer ignorance. Is there anything you can do?
我们一定会尝试，感染非常严重
We'll certainly try. The infection is massive.
让我给你打一针来缓解疼痛
Let me give you a hypo to ease the pain.
- 哪里？  - 在手臂上
- Where? - In the arm.
菲拉娜，他们是来帮忙的，他们不该死
Philana, they came to help. They deserve better than to die.
亚历山大，你说得太多了
Alexander, you talk too much.
柯克：宇宙，最后的边疆
KIRK: Space, the final frontier.
这些是星舰企业号的航程
These are the voyages of the starship Enterprise.
它的五年任务：探索未知的新世界
Its five-year mission: To explore strange new worlds,
寻找新生命和新文明
to seek out new life and new civilizations,
勇踏前人未至之境
to boldly go where no man has gone before.
柯克：舰长日志，星历5784.3
KIRK: Captain's log, stardate 5784.3.
麦考伊医生正在治疗一群人的领袖
Dr. McCoy is treating the leader of a group of people.
当他们的星球被新星爆发毁灭
When their planet novaed,
他们在苏格拉底和柏拉图的时代来到地球
they travelled to Earth during the time of Socrates and Plato.
希腊文明消亡后
After the death of Greek civilization,
他们来到这个星球并创造了一个以它为原型的乌托邦
they came to this planet and created a utopia patterned after it.
- 怎么样？你的预后是什么？  - 当我有结果时我会告诉你
- What is it? What is your prognosis? - I'll tell you when I have the results.
从现在，不用你帮忙，我自己操纵仪器比较好
From now on, it's better if I handle the instruments without your help.
我不明白为什么伤口变得如此严重
I can't understand why a cut became so serious.
我也不
Neither do I.
我如何在没有关于柏拉图星细菌的信息的情况下消除感染？
How do I knock out an infection with no information on Platonius bacteria?
我所能做的就是尝试将他的细菌与已知的菌株相匹配，并祈祷
All I can do is try to match his bugs with a known strain, and hope.
- 你的潘神处于危险之中  - 嗯嗯…
- Your Pan is in jeopardy. - Mm-hm...
现在不是，我赢了！
It isn't now. I win!
- 干得漂亮，赫拉克利特  - 谢谢
- Well played, Eraclitus. - Thank you.
你的这种念力…
This psychokinetic power of yours...
- 你有这个能力多长时间了？  - 两个半…
- How long have you had it? - Two and a half...
- 自从我们到达柏拉图星  - 它是如何传输的？
- Since our arrival on Platonius. - How is it transmitted?
脑波
Brain waves.
- 当你睡着时它们会停止吗？  - 如果嵌入无意识，则不会
- Do they cease while you're asleep? - Not if embedded in the unconscious.
医学呢？没有医生？
What about medicine? No doctors?
我们对医学技能没有迫切的需求
We've had no pressing need for the medical arts.
还在桑达纳星时，我们开始了大规模优生计划
While still on Sahndara, we began a mass eugenics program.
我们就是成果
We're the result.
减少到38人，我们非常适合我们的乌托邦
Pared down to 38, we're perfect for our utopia.
我们是为沉思和自力更生而生的
We're bred for contemplation, and self-reliance.
而且长寿，你说我几岁？
And longevity. How old would you say I am?
不要害怕，我不虚荣
Don't be afraid. I'm not vain.
- 35  - 这么老？
- Thirty-five. - That old?
我在30岁停止衰老，无论如何，你差了2000年年
I stopped aging at 30. Anyway, you're off by 2,000 years.
我今年2300岁
I'm 2,300 years old.
我们很年轻就结婚了，我当时只有117岁
We were married very young. I was only 117.
他128岁
And he was 128.
所以我们几乎不必再搬家了，更不用说工作了
So we scarcely have to move anymore, let alone work.
- 所以你没有抵抗力？  - 是的
- So you have no resistance? - That's right.
皮肤破裂或割伤可能是致命的
A break in the skin or a cut can be fatal.
[呜咽]
[WHIMPERS]
真有趣
Fascinating.
我们正在体验他神志失常的意念运动表现
We're experiencing the psychokinetic manifestations of his delirium.
斯科特呼叫柯克舰长
Scott to Captain Kirk.
- 柯克呼叫企业号  - 我们正处于风暴之中
- Kirk to Enterprise. - We're in the midst of a storm.
没有明显的原因，我从未见过类似的东西
No discernible cause. I've never seen anything like it.
有10级湍流
There's 10-scale turbulence.
紧急陀螺仪和稳定器开到了最大
Emergency gyros and stabilizers at maximum.
如果一直这样，我们就撑不下去了
If this keeps up, we can't last.
引擎全速运转，让她脱离轨道
Engines at full speed. Get her out of orbit.
我试过了，先生，她被锁得很紧
I've tried that, sir. She's locked tight.
- 那就准备好迎接风暴吧  - 好的，舰长
- Then batten down and weather. - Right, Captain.
帕门的想法不是…小心！
Parmen's mind is not... Watch it!
他也在撕毁企业号，老骨头，把他打倒
He's tearing up the Enterprise as well. Bones, knock him out.
救命！救救我！
Help! Save me!
亚历山大，哦！
Alexander. Oooh!
- 站在我身后  - 他的头脑无论如何都会找到我的
- Stand behind me. - His mind will find me anyhow.
不要救他，让他死
Don't save him. Let him die.
他们会为了取代他的位置而互相残杀
They'll kill each other trying to take his place.
- 快点开枪  - 就是现在，医生！
- Hurry up with that shot. - Now, Doctor!
我无法呼吸！我窒息了！
I can't breathe! I'm choking!
老骨头！摇晃他，分散他的注意力
Bones! Shake him, break his concentration.
柯克呼叫企业号
Kirk to Enterprise.
湍流已经减弱
The turbulence has abated.
你会发现轨道锁也坏了
You'll find the orbit lock is broken as well.
评估损坏并进行必要的修理
Assess damage and repair whatever is necessary.
我不知道如何感谢你，为柏拉图星和我自己
I don't know how to thank you, for Platonius and for myself.
- 不需要感谢  - 带我们的客人到南翼
- No thanks is necessary. - Show our guests to the south wing.
谢谢你，我们必须回到船上
Thank you, we must return to the ship.
我最好等到退烧了
I'd better wait until the fever breaks.
好…
Well...
以防万一，我们会留下来
In that case, we'll stay.
- 你想要什么，尽管说  - 谢谢
- Anything you want, just ask me. - Thank you.
不用谢，你救了我的命，我应该告诉你…
Think nothing of it, you saved my life. I should tell you that...
- 告诉我什么？  - 好…
- Tell me what? - Well...
- 我从来不知道像你这样的人存在  - 大家在哪里？
- I never knew people like you existed. - Where is everyone?
他们都在房间里，冥想
They're all in chambers, meditating.
亚历山大…
Alexander...
还有像你一样的柏拉图人吗？
Are there other Platonians like you?
- “像我一样”是什么意思？  - 没有意念运动能力的人
- What do you mean "like me"? - Who don't have psychokinetic ability.
我以为你在说我的体型
I thought you were talking about my size.
他们取笑我的体型
They make fun of me for my size.
但我是唯一没有念力的人
But I'm the only one who doesn't have it.
我是宫廷小丑
I'm the court buffoon.
我是所有人的奴隶，我永远都是错的
I'm everybody's slave and I never do anything right.
- 如何获得能力？  - 它是生来就有的
- How does one obtain the power? - It just comes to you after you're born.
他们说我是一个返祖者，我是，你也是
They say I'm a throwback. And I am, and so are you.
- 对不起，我不应该那样说  - 别担心，我们很高兴没有它
- Sorry, I shouldn't have said that. - Don't worry. We're happy without it.
你知道，我相信你是
You know, I believe you are.
在你的故乡，有人多没有念力
Where you come from, are there a lot of people without the power
和我一样体型的人吗？
and my size?
亚历山大，在我的故乡，高矮，胖瘦，或肤色没有区别
Alexander, where I come from, size, shape or colour makes no difference.
没有人有念力
And nobody has the power.
没有人？
Nobody?
有人叫我
Somebody wants me.
舰长，离开这里会很高兴的
Captain, it will be very gratifying to leave here.
那可能并不容易，如果帕门死了
That might not be easy, should Parmen die.
- 即使他不死也很难  - 是的
- Even if he shouldn't. - Yes.
这个乌托邦是银河系中保存最完好的秘密之一
This utopia is one of the best-kept secrets in the galaxy.
屏蔽我们的传感器，将我们锁定在轨道上
Screening themselves from our sensors, locking us into orbit.
所有这些加起来就是一个模式
All this adds up to a pattern.
吉姆，我的药方奏效了，退烧了
Jim, my concoction worked, the fever's broken.
感染已经开始消退
And the infection's begun to drain already.
- 你也许还能治好普通感冒  - 如果要走，就是现在
- You may yet cure the common cold. - If there's a time to go, it's now.
- 我是斯科特  - 柯克[通过无线电]：传送我们上去
- Scott, here. - KIRK [OVER RADIO]: Beam us up.
- 我不能，一切都冻结了  - 湍流的伤害这么大吗？
- I can't. Everything's frozen. - Turbulence hit you that hard?
- 船的损伤很小  - 那是什么引起的？
- Damage to the ship is minimal. - What caused it?
我不知道，先生，但事实如此
I don't know, sir. And those are the facts.
- 你进入太空了吗？  - 轨道的引力比以往更大
- Did you get up into space? - The orbit's locked tighter than ever.
与星际舰队的子空间通信被完全切断
And subspace communication with Starfleet is completely severed.
好吧，斯科提，我会在这里处理，待命
All right, Scotty. I'll handle it down here. Stand by.
♪ 伟大的潘神吹响他的号角 ♪
♪ Great Pan sounds his horn ♪
♪ 用他的蹄子打着拍子 ♪
♪ Marking time to the rhyme with his hoof ♪
♪ 用他的蹄子 ♪
♪ With his hoof ♪
♪ 前进，按计划前进 ♪
♪ Forward, forward in our plan ♪
♪ 我们按原样继续 ♪
♪ We proceed as we began ♪
♪ 布雷凯凯凯克斯，布雷凯凯凯克斯… ♪
♪ Breki-kekecks, breki-kekecks... ♪
- 阁下  - 帕门会做的
- Your Excellency. - Parmen will do.
哲人王不需要头衔
Philosopher-kings need no titles.
我想知道为什么船上的仪器被冻结了
I would like to know why the ship's instrumentation is frozen.
- 为什么企业号被锁定在轨道上  - 舰长，请，你误会了
- Why the Enterprise is locked in orbit. - Captain, please. You are mistaken.
我已经和船上的轮机长谈过了
I've talked to the engineer aboard the ship.
我们已经表明了我们的诚意，现在你展示你的
We've shown our good faith. Now you show yours.
- 我要立即释放这艘船  - 设施
- I want the ship released immediately. - The amenities.
请允许我提醒您，我是这个公国的首领
Allow me to remind you that I am the head of this principality.
客人不会闯入这里提出要求，发布命令
Guests do not come barging in here making demands and issuing orders.
客人？你不知道这个词的意思
Guests? You don't know the meaning of the word.
- 客人不会被当作囚犯对待  - 不要用那种语气跟我说话
- Guests aren't treated like prisoners. - Do not take that tone with me.
柯克呼叫企业号，请回答
Kirk to Enterprise. Acknowledge.
企业号，请回答…我无法联系他们
Enterprise, come in... I can't raise them.
帕门不想我们与企业号联系
Parmen does not want contact made with the Enterprise.
他可能需要我们的医疗补给，为什么要禁止联系？
He may need our medical stores. Why prevent contact?
为了不让外界知道他是如何对待一位星际舰队舰长的
To shut out any knowledge of his treatment of a Starfleet captain.
帕门不关心我的尊严或安全
Parmen is not concerned with my dignity or safety.
帕门不会粗暴地对待你
Parmen would not treat you brutally
如果他有任何释放你或企业号的意图
if he had any intention of releasing you or the Enterprise.
你要去哪里？
Where are you going?
我不知道，我不想去，但我控制不住自己
I don't know. I don't want to go but I can't help myself.
[吹号角]
[PLAYS FANFARE]
善良的太空人，我们永远欠你的人情
Gentle spacemen. We are eternally in your debt.
请收下这些东西作为谢礼
Please accept these trifles as tokens of gratitude,
来自我们灵感的源头
from the source of our inspiration.
赠予我们的舰长
To our captain,
伯里克利举过的盾牌，象征英勇的领导
the shield carried by Pericles, a symbol of gallant leadership.
赠予我们沉默而理智的史波克先生
To our silent and cerebral Mr. Spock,
这把西塞拉琴，它弹拨的乐曲能抚平他紧锁的眉头
this kithara to pluck music to soothe his ever-active brow.
最后，赠予拯救了柏拉图星和我配偶的麦考伊医生
And lastly, to Dr. McCoy who saved Platonius and my spouse,
这本古老的希腊疗法集，由希波克拉底本人撰写
this ancient collection of Greek cures, penned by Hippocrates himself.
企业号被释放了吗？
Has the Enterprise been released yet?
舰长，等等
Captain, wait.
我知道你在想什么，我很抱歉，对你的态度很恶劣
I know what you're thinking. My apologies, you were badly used.
我要为自己辩护，我的病比我意识到的更令人不安
In my own defence, my illness was more disturbing than I realised.
我相信你也有过失态的时候
I'm sure you, too, have been out of sorts
也有过被迫发脾气和发怒的时候
and driven to fits of temper and rage.
但与你不同的是，我的想法和感受，无论好坏
But unlike you, what I think and feel, for good or ill,
瞬间转化为现实，在你的心中找到原谅我的理由吧
is instantly translated into reality. Find it in your heart to forgive me.
当然
Certainly.
企业号被释放了吗？
Has the Enterprise been released yet?
很快就会了
It will be shortly.
- 那么日安，谢谢你  - 不用谢
- Then good day, and thank you. - Not at all.
最后还有一个要求
There is one final request.
在我几乎致命的感染之后，它变得很明显
After my nearly fatal infection, it has become obvious
我们不能没有医生
that we cannot afford to be without a physician.
我们希望你留下来，麦考伊医生
We should like you, Dr. McCoy, to remain.
对不起，那是不可能的
I'm sorry, that's impossible.
你的职责会格外轻松
Your duties will be extraordinarily light.
你可以自由地阅读，冥想，进行研究，随你喜欢
You shall be free to read, meditate, conduct research, whatever you like.
答案是不
The answer is no.
我们想保持亲切，但是…
We should like to keep it cordial, but...
我们决心让你留下来，医生
we are determined to have you stay, Doctor.
- 麦考伊医生救了你的命  - 我快失去耐心了
- Dr. McCoy saved your life. - I am losing patience.
- 你是柏拉图的信徒？  - 我们生活在和平与和谐中
- You are a disciple of Plato? - We live in peace and harmony.
谁的和谐？你的？柏拉图想要真理和美
Whose harmony? Yours? Plato wanted truth and beauty.
并且，最重要的是，正义
And, above all, justice.
亲爱的史波克先生
My dear Mr. Spock,
环境迫使我们对柏拉图进行一些改编
circumstances have forced us to make a few adaptations of Plato.
但我们的社会是可以想象的最民主的社会
But ours is the most democratic society conceivable.
任何人都可以在任何时候成为或做任何他想做的事
Anyone can, at any moment, be or do anything he wishes,
甚至成为柏拉图星的统治者，如果他的思想足够强大的话
even become ruler of Platonius, if his mind is strong enough.
如果他的思想不强大，他会像亚历山大一样被撕裂？
If his mind isn't strong, he's torn apart like Alexander?
我们不是孩子
We are not children.
在你们的文化中，正义是强者的意志
In your culture, justice is the will of the stronger.
它是通过武器，宇宙飞船强加给人们的
It is forced upon people by means of weapons, spaceships.
我们的正义是更强大的思想的意志，是巨大的进步
Our justice is the will of the stronger mind, a vast improvement.
我们不会使用武器来实施你这样的暴行
We don't use weapons for the brutality you practise.
再见了，舰长
Farewell, Captain.
走吧
Come on.
麦考伊
McCoy.
我不能动，无论如何他们都要把我留在这里
I can't move. They're gonna keep me here no matter what.
- 请离开  - 不，你是医生
- Leave, please. - No, you're the doctor.
他们不想强迫你，他们正在努力…
They don't want to force you. They're trying...
趁你们还可以的时候赶紧走
Go while you still can.
我们不走，除非放开他
We're not leaving till he's released.
你没有指挥权
You are not in command.
- 为什么要争这个？赶他们走  - 那可能会冒犯医生
- Why discuss it? Get rid of them. - That might offend the doctor.
你想留下来吗？无论如何
You wish to stay? By all means.
帮助我们庆祝我们的周年纪念日
Help us celebrate our anniversary.
我希望我们能说服你加入我们这个小小的理想国
I hope we can persuade you to join our tiny republic.
- 你不会说服我的  - 我想我们会的
- You won't persuade me. - I think we will.
♪ 特威帝，特威丹，太空人踩着鼓点前进 ♪
♪ Tweedledee, Tweedledum Spacemen marching to a drum ♪
♪ 我们在mimsytoves间滑行并在borogoves间回旋 ♪
♪ We slithe among the mimsy toves And gyre among the borogoves ♪
你不要留下来，麦考伊，不管他…
You're not staying, McCoy, no matter what he...
做你的奴隶
Being your slave,
我该做什么
what should I do
除了每时
but tend upon the hours
每刻…遵从你的愿望？
and times... of your desire?
我没有宝贵的时间可以度过
I have no precious time at all to spend
也没有服务要做，直到你…
Nor service to do, till you...
停下！不要这样对他，帕门
Stop it! Don't do this to him, Parmen.
麦考伊，不管他让我说什么或做什么
McCoy, no matter what he makes me say or do,
答案是…不
the answer's... no.
不，帕门！停下来！
No, Parmen! Stop it!
怎么，医生？
Well, Doctor?
我…
I...
我有我的命令
I have my orders.
如你所愿，医生
As you wish, Doctor.
这是你的乌托邦吗？你对未来的宏伟愿景？
Is this your utopia? Your grand vision of the future?
你甚至不…
You don't even...
[尖叫]
[SCREAMS]
- 受够你的说教了  - 我们也受够了
- Enough of your moralising. - We've had too much of yours.
- 你永远别想让我留下来  - 你会很高兴的
- You'll never get me to stay. - You'll be happy to.
这需要时间，但你会很高兴留下来的
It takes time, but you will be happy to stay.
他是瓦肯人！你不能强迫他流露情绪
He's a Vulcan! You can't force emotion out of him.
- 你一定是在开玩笑  - 你会毁了他
- You must be joking. - You'll destroy him.
我们总不能让他笑死吧？
We can't let him die laughing, can we?
[呜咽]
[SOBS]
我求你…
I beg you...
史波克…
Spock...
不要…让他们毁了你
Don't... let them break you.
坚持住！
Hold on!
别…
Don't...
帕门，他们救了你的命！
Parmen, they saved your life!
身为柏拉图人我感到羞耻，羞耻！
I'm ashamed to be a Platonian. Ashamed!
[嘶声]
[WHINNIES]
你怎么能让这种情况继续发生？
How can you let this go on?
- 你能做什么吗？  - 没有药物可以帮助
- Can you do anything? - No medicine can help.
他必须自己挺过来
He'll have to come through this himself.
我相信他们没有对你造成太大伤害，舰长？
I trust they did not injure you too much, Captain?
我的肌肉酸痛，仅此而已
My muscles are sore, that's all.
屈辱一定是最难以忍受的
The humiliation must have been most difficult to bear.
我能理解
I can understand.
情绪的释放使我们保持健康
The release of emotions is what keeps us healthy.
- 情绪健康，就是这样  - 那可能是，医生
- Emotionally healthy, that is. - That may be, Doctor.
然而，我注意到情绪的健康释放
However, I have noted that the healthy release of emotion
对你最亲近的人来说，通常是非常不健康的
is frequently very unhealthy for those closest to you.
这证明没有完美的解决方案
Which goes to prove there's no perfect solution.
看起来是这样
So it would seem.
- 舰长  - 是的，史波克
- Captain. - Yes, Spock.
你还对帕门感到愤怒吗？
Do you still feel anger toward Parmen?
巨大的愤怒
Great anger.
- 你呢，麦考伊医生？  - 是的，还有仇恨
- And you, Dr. McCoy? - Yes, and hatred.
那么你必须释放它，先生们
Then you must release it, gentlemen,
因为我必须控制我的
as I must master mine.
我可能会严重伤害你，舰长
I might have seriously injured you, Captain,
甚至杀了你
even killed you.
他们在我心中激起了如此巨大的仇恨
They have evoked such great hatred in me,
我不能让它更进一步
I cannot allow it to go further.
我必须…
I must...
…控制它
...master it.
我必须…控制…
I must... control...
吉姆…
Jim...
这是毫无意义的，我会留下来
This is senseless. I'm staying.
- 你不能  - 帕门答应你会安全的
- You can't. - Parmen promised you'll be safe.
他会传送上去，然后将船推回大气层
He'd let us beam up then plunge the ship back into the atmosphere.
为什么要骗我？
Why trick me?
因为如果他直接杀了我们，你会报复的
Because if he killed us outright, you'd retaliate.
你是医生，你有办法
You're a doctor, you have the means.
老骨头，我知道你正在努力做正确的事情
Bones, I know you're trying to do the right thing,
但如果我们中的任何一个人逃脱了
but if any one of us escaped,
帕门知道星际舰队永远不会让这个星球逍遥法外
Parmen knows Starfleet would never let this planet go unpunished.
你的牺牲就等于签署了我们的死刑令
Sacrifice yourself and you sign our death warrant.
他是对的，我应该警告你的
He's right. I should have warned you.
他们对待你们就像对待我一样
They were treating you the same way they treat me.
只是你们与他们作斗争了
Only you fight them.
一直以来，我都以为是我的问题，我的思维移动不了一块鹅卵石
All the time, I thought it was me, my mind couldn't move a pebble.
他们甚至告诉我，留在他们身边是我的幸运，而我相信了他们
They even told me I was lucky they kept me around, and I believed them.
被每个人心血来潮地呼来唤去
The arms and legs of everybody's whim.
低眉顺目，不能直视他们，保持微笑
Look down, don't meet their eyes. Smile.
这些强大的人，对我来说他们是神
These great people, they were gods to me.
但你向我展示了他们的真实面目
But you showed me what they really are.
现在我知道了，错的不是我，不是我的体型，而是他们
And now I know, it's not me, it's not my size, it's them.
是他们！
It's them!
- 放下它  - 不，这是最好的选择
- Put it down. - No, this is the best thing.
- 照我说的做  - 我要杀了他们
- Do what I say. - I'm gonna cut them.
首先是帕门，然后他们都会被感染，但这一次，让他们去死吧
Parmen first, and they'll all get infected. But this time, let them die.
让他们尝尝他们给我的滋味
Let me give them a taste of what they gave me.
反正他们会杀了你
They're gonna kill you, anyway.
既然如此，你死了又有什么意义呢？
In that case, what's the point in you dying too?
把它给我
Give it to me.
这是第一次有人把我的生命置于他自己的生命之上
That's the first time anybody ever thought of my life before his own.
我应该在你们刚来的时候告诉你们他们要杀了你们
I should have told you when you first came that they were gonna kill you.
- 我当时很害怕  - 没关系
- I was afraid. - It's all right.
没关系，亚历山大
It's all right, Alexander.
我们还没有放弃
We haven't given up.
也许你可以做些什么来提供帮助
And there may be something you can do to help.
- 任何事，只要你说  - 好的
- Anything, you just tell me. - All right.
柏拉图人一直都拥有这种力量吗？
Did the Platonians always have this power?
- 不，我们来到这个星球后  - 亚历山大
- No, not until we came to this planet. - Alexander.
你能记得你们到达后多久
Is it possible for you to recall how long after you arrived
他们的力量开始发展？
that their power began to develop?
我们到达这里六个月后，他们开始到处推我
Six months after we got here, they started pushing me around.
你们带了几个月的补给品？
How many months' supplies did you bring with you?
- 四个月，我想…三个月  - 足够接近了
- Four, I think... Three. - That's close enough.
真有趣，他们的力量是在吃过当地食物后发展起来的
Fascinating. Their power developed after eating the native foods.
那就对了
That's right.
有理由假设精神动力与
It's logical to assume a connection between the psychokinetic power
食用本地食物之间存在联系
and eating native foods.
为什么亚历山大没有同样的能力？
Why wouldn't Alexander have the same power?
也许他无法吸收关键元素
Perhaps he cannot absorb the crucial element.
老骨头，测一下亚历山大的血液
Bones, take a reading of Alexander's blood.
不是我害怕，但这会痛吗？
Not that I'm afraid, but will it hurt much?
你甚至不会知道它发生了
You won't even know it happened.
你有帕门血液的读数
You have a reading of Parmen's blood.
他有最强的意念运动能力
He has the highest psychokinetic ability
在同等条件下，亚历山大最弱
and Alexander the lowest, in the same conditions.
相较柏拉图人亚历山大可能有生化缺陷
Alexander probably has a biochemical deficiency relative to Platonius.
我将运行两个样本进行比较测试
I'll run both samples through for a comparative test.
如果我们的理论成立，我们就有了武器
If our theory works out, we've got a weapon.
帕门和亚历山大血液的区别
The difference between Parmen's blood and Alexander's
是被激素分解的基洛奈德的浓度
is the concentration of kironide broken down by hormone.
基洛奈德，一种高能量的资源，可能就是这样
Kironide. A high-energy source. That could be it.
激素证实了这一假设，它们还调节身体生长
The hormones confirm the hypothesis. They also regulate body growth.
你的意思是…
You mean...
我没有力量和我成为侏儒是同一个原因？
The same thing that kept me from having the power made me a dwarf?
是的，同样显而易见的是，巴门为什么要保守这个乌托邦的秘密
Yes. It's also obvious why Parmen kept this utopia secret.
任何人在这里呆久了都会获得力量
Anyone remaining here long enough would acquire the power.
正是
Exactly.
一定有快速的方法在我们的血液中积累基洛奈德
There must be a quick way of building up kironide in our blood.
- 这是可能的  - 我们还在等什么？
- It's possible. - What are we waiting for?
它是什么？
What is it?
即使基洛奈德有效果，也未必能帮我们脱身
Even if the kironide has an effect, it may not help us get out.
- 是的，他们有38个人  - 有道理
- Yes, there are 38 of them. - Point taken.
但这种力量是不能累加的
But the power is not additive.
否则考虑到柏拉图人的倾向
If it were, considering the Platonians propensities,
两三个人会联合起来废黜帕门
two or three would have combined forces and deposed Parmen.
他是对的
He's right.
帕门说每个人都有自己的力量频率
Parmen says each has his own power frequency.
他们试过结合他们的力量，从未成功
When they tried to combine their powers, it never worked.
- 我准备好了  - 我们不要浪费时间了
- I'm ready. - Let's not waste time.
给我们双倍于帕门血液中的浓度
Give us double the concentration in Parmen's blood.
时间因素让我很担心
The time factor concerns me.
可能需要几天的时间才能有利好我们的足够的基洛奈德
It may take days before there's enough kironide to benefit us.
是的
Yes.
亚历山大呢？
What about Alexander?
由于基洛奈德直接注入他的血液
Since the kironide's injected directly into his blood,
应该对他更有效，因为他已经适应了
it should work on him better because he's acclimated.
噢，不，不是在他们对我做了什么之后
Oh, no. Not after what they've done to me.
为什么不？你可以取代帕门的位置并管理整个星球
Why not? You could take Parmen's place and run the whole planet.
你认为那是我想要的吗？成为其中之一？
You think that's what I want? To become one of them?
成为我自己的敌人？
Become my own enemy?
躺着不动所有事情都由别人为我做好？
Lie around like a big blob and have things done for me?
我想为自己走动，为自己笑或哭
I want to move around for myself, laugh or cry for myself.
你可以保留你宝贵的力量
You can keep your precious power.
我只要求一件事，如果你们能离开这里，带上我
All I ask is one thing. If you make it out of here, take me with you.
把我带到没人听说过基洛奈德或柏拉图星的任何地方
Drop me any place they never heard of kironide or Platonius.
柯克：护士…
KIRK: Nurse...
乌胡拉上尉…
Lieutenant Uhura...
我想我们不够有趣
I guess we weren't sufficiently entertaining.
我们很高兴见到你！
Are we glad to see you!
我们被迫传送下来
We were forced to beam down.
仿佛变成了某人的傀儡
It was like becoming someone's puppet.
我以为我在梦游，我无法阻止自己
I thought I was sleepwalking. I couldn't stop myself.
[笑声]
[LAUGHTER]
舰长，怎么了？发生了什么？
Captain, what is it? What's going on?
- 你觉得基洛奈德有什么效果吗？  - 我有一点燥热
- Do you feel any effect of the kironide? - I experienced a slight flush.
我也是，让我们尝试一个简单的测试
So did I. Let's try a simple test.
全神贯注提升这盘水果
Concentrate on raising this plate of fruit.
没有反应
Nothing.
[掌声]
[APPLAUSE]
各位学者，2500年前
Fellow academicians, 2,500 years ago,
一群热情的流浪者来到了这个粗犷的星球
a band of hearty vagabonds arrived on this rough-hewn planet.
穷困，辛劳
There was hardship, back-breaking toil,
神圣的眷顾使我们的天才和奉献精神具有力量的力量
and then a divine providence graced our genius and dedication
通过它，我们的每一个需求立即实现
with the power of powers, and through it our every need instantly materialised.
我们于是决定成立一个乌托邦兄弟会
We thereupon determined to form a Utopian Brotherhood.
这是一个喜庆的时刻，因为今晚我们欢迎它的第一个新成员
This is a festive occasion, for tonight we welcome into that brotherhood
加入这个兄弟会
its first new member.
还没有，帕门，你必须先说服医生
Not yet, Parmen. You have to convince the doctor first.
他们永远都做不到，吉姆
They'll never do it, Jim.
医生，拜托，你破坏了女士们的节日气氛
Doctor, please, you have destroyed the festive mood of the ladies.
我们必须立即活跃气氛
We must recapture it at once.
我想到了
I know.
有什么比笑着的太空人唱小夜曲更好的呢？
What would be better than a serenade from the laughing spaceman?
♪ 小心，年轻的女士们，珍惜你们的酒 ♪
♪ Take care young ladies and value your wine ♪
♪ 警惕风华正茂的年轻男人 ♪
♪ Be watchful of young men in their velvet prime ♪
♪ 他们会深深地吞下你最好的酒 ♪
♪ Deeply they'll swallow from your finest kegs ♪
♪ 然后迅速消失 ♪
♪ Then swiftly be gone ♪
♪ 留下苦渣 ♪
♪ Leaving bitter dregs ♪
♪ 啊啊-啊啊 ♪
♪ Aaaah-aaaah ♪
♪ 苦渣 ♪
♪ Bitter dregs ♪
♪ 用微笑的话语，温柔的抚摸做幌子 ♪
♪ With smiling words and tender touch ♪
♪ 男人给予的少，而索取的多 ♪
♪ Man offers little and asks for so much ♪
♪ 他在夜晚令人窒息的兴奋中爱你 ♪
♪ He loves in the breathless excitement of night ♪
♪ 然后带着你的财宝在寒冷的晨光中离开 ♪
♪ Then leaves with your treasure in cold morning light ♪
♪ 啊啊-啊啊 ♪
♪ Aaaah-aaaah ♪
♪ 在寒冷的晨光中 ♪
♪ In cold morning light ♪
现在，让狂欢开始吧
Now, let the revels begin.
[人群笑]
[CROWD LAUGHS]
[掌声]
[APPLAUSE]
多么不忠和善变
How faithless and fickle.
做个决定！
Make up your minds!
我很难为情，请让他们停下来
I'm so ashamed. Please, make them stop.
我们已经试过了
We have tried.
拜托，请让他们停下来
Please, please make them stop.
我没有那个能力
I haven't the power.
我深感抱歉
I'm deeply sorry.
我们辜负了你
We've failed you.
这么久以来，我一直想靠近你
For so long, I've wanted to be close to you.
现在我只想爬走然后死去
Now all I want to do is crawl away and die.
小心，史波克先生，过多的爱是危险的
Careful, Mr. Spock, too much love is dangerous.
请记住，丘比特的箭会杀死瓦肯人
Remember, Cupid's arrow kills Vulcans.
我好害怕，舰长，我非常害怕
I'm so frightened, Captain. I'm so very frightened.
这就是他们希望你感受到的，这让他们觉得自己还活着
That's the way they want you to feel. It makes them think they're alive.
我知道
I know it.
但是…我希望我能停止颤抖
But... I wish I could stop trembling.
尽量不要…去想它们
Try not... to think of them.
试试！
Try!
我在想…
I'm thinking...
…想起了在企业号上每次吓到要死的时候
...of all the times on the Enterprise when I was scared to death.
我看到你那么忙于指挥
And I would see you so busy at your commands,
我能从船上的各个角落听到你的声音
and I would hear your voice from all parts of the ship,
然后我的恐惧就会消退
and my fears would fade.
现在你的声音让我颤抖
And now they're making me tremble.
但我并不害怕
But I'm not afraid.
我不害怕
I am not afraid.
[笑声和掌声]
[LAUGHTER AND APPLAUSE]
帕门，让我们继续吧
Parmen, let's get on with it.
你太没耐心了，观察医生，学习
You are so impatient. Observe the doctor and learn.
他很满意地等待着重头戏
He's content to wait for the pièce de résistance.
你们都半死了，你们所有人
You're half dead, all of you.
你们已经死了几个世纪了
You've been dead for centuries.
我们明天可能会消失，但我们现在还活着
We may disappear tomorrow, but we're living now.
你们接受不了事实
You can't stand that.
你们半疯了，因为内心空虚
You're half crazy because there's nothing inside.
你们必须折磨我们才能说服自己你们是优越的
You have to torture us to convince yourselves you're superior.
住手，帕门！
Stop it, Parmen!
我会做任何你想做的，我会为你服务，住手！
I'll do whatever you want, I'll serve you, but stop it!
帕门
Parmen.
又是亚历山大
Alexander again.
他喜欢玩刀，很好，我们会满足他的
He likes to play with knives. Very well, we shall indulge him.
谁干的？
Who did that?
- 我干的  - 不可能的！
- I did. - Impossible!
很有可能，并且合乎逻辑
Quite possible. And logical.
- 怎么了？  - 这是怎么回事？
- What is it? - What's going on?
柏拉图人，下一个试着耍花招的人，都会受到伤害
Platonians, the next one of you that tries any trick, will get hurt.
我们拥有两倍于你们的力量水平的意念运动能力
We have your psychokinetic ability at twice your power level.
不是我的两倍
Not twice mine.
舰长，不！
Captain, no!
我求你，我会做你所说的任何事情
I beg of you, I'll do anything you say.
我不想死
I do not wish to die.
舰长？你听到我了吗？
Captain? Do you hear me?
不要阻止我，让我干掉他！
Don't stop me. Let me finish him off!
你想和他一样吗？
You want to be like him?
帕门，听我说，我本可以拥有你的力量，但我不想要它
Parmen, listen to me. I could have had your power, but I didn't want it.
我现在就可以拥有你的位置
I could have had your place right now.
但是看到你和你的学者们让我感到恶心
But the sight of you and your Academicians sickens me.
你是这世上最卑鄙的东西
You're the most contemptible things in this universe.
舰长，你知道我打算摧毁你和企业号
Captain. You knew I intended to destroy both you and the Enterprise.
然而你却饶了我
Yet you spared me.
对我们来说，杀人就是谋杀，即使是为了复仇
To us, killing is murder, even for revenge.
会有其他的星舰…
There will be other starships...
无需担心，他们会是安全的
No need for concern. They'll be safe.
我开始觉得我们变得怪异和没有生产力
I've begun to think we've become bizarre and unproductive,
只是为了滋养我们的力量而存在，是时候呼吸新鲜空气了
existing merely to nourish our powers, it's time for fresh air.
- 我们欢迎你的光临  - 我不相信你
- We'll welcome your visits. - I don't believe you.
那将是不寻常的
That would be uncharacteristic.
我们必须预料到，当我们离开这里的那一刻，你们的恐惧就会消失
We must expect that the moment we leave here, your fear will be gone.
你们会再次变得残酷和傲慢
You'll again be as sadistic and arrogant
正如2500年来的你们样子
as your 2,500 years have made you.
我们可以在几个小时内重新创造这种力量
We can recreate that power in a matter of hours.
所以不要试图耍花招
So don't try anything.
明白了，舰长
Understood, Captain.
你说得对，我们谁都不可信
And you're right, none of us can be trusted.
不受控制的权力甚至会将圣人变成野蛮人
Uncontrolled, power will turn even saints into savages.
我们都活在最低级的冲动中
We all live down to our lowest impulses.
你很擅长演讲
You're very good at making speeches.
只要确保这一点能被理解
Just make sure that this one sinks in.
现在让开
Now move aside.
亚历山大
Alexander.
柯克呼叫企业号，斯科特先生，准备传送我们上去
Kirk to Enterprise. Mr. Scott, prepare to beam us up.
我有一个小惊喜给你
I have a little surprise for you.
我要带一位访客上船
I'm bringing a visitor aboard.